<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://lch32111.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://lch32111.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2023-01-14T15:56:19+00:00</updated><id>https://lch32111.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Floating Point Number</title><link href="https://lch32111.github.io/blog/2022/Floating-Point-Number/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Floating Point Number"/><published>2022-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lch32111.github.io/blog/2022/Floating-Point-Number</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lch32111.github.io/blog/2022/Floating-Point-Number/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="floating-point-number">Floating Point Number</h1> <p>Floating Point Number is represented in a computer according to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IEEE_754">IEEE 754</a>.</p> <p>According to the wikipedia, the format is specified by:</p> <ul> <li>base (or <em>radix</em>) \(b\), which is either 2 (binary) or 10 (decimal) in IEEE 754;</li> <li>a precision \(p\);</li> <li>an exponent range from \(emin\) to \(emax\), with \(emin = 1 - emax\) for all IEEE 754 formats.</li> </ul> <p>The format can describe the next values</p> <ul> <li>Finite numbers <ul> <li>finite numbers are described by three integers</li> <li>\(s\) : a sign (zero or one)</li> <li>\(c\) : a significant (or coefficient) having no more than \(p\) digits when written in base \(b\). (i.e., an integer in the range through 0 to \(b^p - 1\))</li> <li>\(q\) : an exponent such that \(emin \le q + p - 1 \le emax\).</li> <li>The numerical value of such a finite number is \((-1)^s \times c \times b^q\)</li> <li>There are two zero values, called <em>signed zeros</em>: the sign bit specifies whether a zero is +0 (positive zero) or -0 (negative zero).</li> </ul> </li> <li>Two infinities: \(+\infty\) and \(-\infty\).</li> <li>Two kinds of NaN (not-a-number): a quiet NaN (qNaN) and a signaling NaN (sNaN).</li> </ul> <p>The next illustration shows the layout for 32-bit floating point:</p> <p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d2/Float_example.svg/885px-Float_example.svg.png" alt="32-bit-floating-point-layout"/></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="CS"/><category term="CS"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[summary for floating point number]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Are You Living Well?</title><link href="https://lch32111.github.io/blog/2022/Are-You-Living-Well/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Are You Living Well?"/><published>2022-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lch32111.github.io/blog/2022/Are-You-Living-Well</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lch32111.github.io/blog/2022/Are-You-Living-Well/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="are-you-living-well">Are You Living Well?</h1> <p>I don’t think I often ask myself this question for some years : Are You Living Well? If you are busy or used to doing repetitive things in your life, you will forget to measure your life. My life has got busier and busier since my military service in Korea. I studied hard to get a job, and then got busier after getting the job. My life has seemed to get complicated more and more as I get old. It’s true. You will have more things to do when you try to leave from the cozy arms of your parents, and have other things more to do when you try to make your own family. You didn’t notice at once that you’ve got raised by many hands. Even I’m currently getting many helps from others. This recognition tends to make me too insane to measure my life, because I need to make it in my life to pay the helps back.</p> <p>While being busy doing my study and my research, I suddenly asked me : are you living well? I couldn’t answer this question easily. I needed a standard of checking whether I’m living well or not. However there are many standards in a life, and it can be hard to measure my life relative to other standards. So, I just found one standard that motivates me. The standard is : Are you enjoying what you are doing?</p> <p>I should be more honest to measure my life with the standard, because I think I must recognize the standard while being busy. I mean that you have to try to measure your life persistently, not at once for some years. The reason is that I often torture myself to make it in my life and rationalize the self-torture. You will lose your health or your precious things even though you think you liked the years you spent and don’t regret the times.</p> <p>​ So If you think you are enjoying what you are doing, I think you can answer “I’m living well now”. This answer will also lead to the answer for “Are you living well for years?” You have to measure your life consciously with the standard every moment. There needs no comparison with others. You can just focus on yourself. Therefore, write what you do in your life, and then find the points you like in your life. I can write now:</p> <ul> <li>Writing this kind of post with a relaxing music (such as Ryuichi Sakamoto’s songs)</li> <li>Solving hard problems on my research and making it work.</li> <li>Walking to the school to study.</li> <li>talking with my loved ones.</li> <li>Exercising</li> <li>Cooking</li> <li>Reading Schopenhauer’s books</li> </ul> <p>When you do the above ones, try to recognize that you enjoy doing them. Then, You will live well.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Thoughts"/><category term="Thoughts"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recognizing your wellness]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hey Gravity Potential Energy</title><link href="https://lch32111.github.io/blog/2022/Hey-Gravity-Potential-Energy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hey Gravity Potential Energy"/><published>2022-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lch32111.github.io/blog/2022/Hey-Gravity-Potential-Energy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lch32111.github.io/blog/2022/Hey-Gravity-Potential-Energy/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="gravitational-energy">Gravitational Energy<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup></h2> <p>I’d like to understand gravitational force<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> and its potential energy<sup id="fnref:3" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote">3</a></sup>. In physics, <strong>potential energy</strong> is “the energy held by an object because of its position relative to other objects, stresses within itself, its electric charge, or other factors”. <strong>work</strong><sup id="fnref:4" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote" rel="footnote">4</a></sup> is “the energy transferred to or from an object via the application of force along a displacement”. Normally the work is the product of force and displacement.</p> <p>To understand more, we often refer to an example of the gravitational energy. If we say that a ball has a \(mgh\) potential energy by the gravity force, and if we lift the ball, then the ball has more potential energy because it has more height from the Earth. However, we need to study more about this. What if the ball is in the infinity distance from the Earth? then the potential energy is infinity?</p> <p>In Newtonian mechanics, two or more masses always pull each other with a gravitational force. This gravitational energy is said to be always negative due to the conservation of energy, to make it zero when the objects are in the infinity distance. With the above example, we can think the \(mgh\) potential energy will not be 0 if the ball keep getting far from the earth. The reason why it’s like that is the \(mgh\) equation is derived when the gravitational energy is assumed as 0 when an object is in the surface of the Earth. so, that’s why there starts to be a point that makes me confused.</p> <p>Therefore, we can think of the \(mgh\) equation as the simple one that makes us understand the idea of potential energy. We can do some math to understand the gravitational energy. By Newton’s law of gravitation,</p> \[F = \frac{GMm}{r^2}\] <p>where \(G\) is the gravitational constant, \(M\) and \(m\) are the mass of two objects, respectively, and \(r\) is the distance between two objects. The work done by this force from infinity to the destination \(R\) is</p> \[W = \int^R_{\infty} \frac{GMm}{r^2} \; dr = - \frac{GMm}{r} \Bigg|^R_{\infty} = -\frac{GMm}{r}\] <p>Since \(W = - \Delta U\) and \(\Delta U = - W = \frac{GMm}{r}\), where \(U\) is potential energy and \(W\) is work. so we can think that, if the gravitational force works on an object from \(x\) to \(y\), then its amount of change of potential energy is \(\Delta U = - \int^y_x \frac{GMm}{r^2} = \frac{GMm}{y} - \frac{GMm}{x}\).</p> <p>So let’s clear our confusing points in this gravitational energy. I really love this answer<sup id="fnref:5" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote" rel="footnote">5</a></sup>. The gravitational potential energy equations are made relative to a frame of reference. This equation \(U = mgh\) depends on the reference that if \(r\) approaches to 0 (which means that an object is in the surface of the earth), its potential energy should be zero. The equation \(U = - \frac{GMm}{r}\) depends on the reference that if \(r\) approaches to 0 (which means that two objects are infinitely far apart ), its potential energy should be zero. Therefore, The first equation says that if the two (an object and the Earth) are far part, the potential energy should increase. The second equation says that if the two (an object and the other) are getting close, the potential energy should increase. You might be confused with the second equation, however you should be careful with the negative sign. If two objects are getting closer, the \(r\) will be smaller, and finally the potential energy gets bigger because it’s minus.</p> <p>So, I think if there is no statement that you should calculate the gravitational potential energy relative to the Earth, then you can just use the \(U = - \frac{GMm}{r}\) which depends on the assumption I told you above.</p> <hr/> <div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes"> <ol> <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote"> <p>Gravitational energy. (2022, September, 14). In Wikipedia. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gravitational_energy <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p> </li> <li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote"> <p>Newton’s law of universal gravitation. (2022, September, 14). In Wikipedia. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Newton%27s_law_of_universal_gravitation <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p> </li> <li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote"> <p>Potential energy. (2022. September, 14). In Wikipedia. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Potential_energy <a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p> </li> <li id="fn:4" role="doc-endnote"> <p>Work (physics). (2022, September, 14). In Wikipedia. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Work_(physics) <a href="#fnref:4" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p> </li> <li id="fn:5" role="doc-endnote"> <p>Why is gravitational potential energy negative, and what does that mean? https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/17082/why-is-gravitational-potential-energy-negative-and-what-does-that-mean <a href="#fnref:5" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p> </li> </ol> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Physics"/><category term="Physics"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[summary for gravitational energy]]></summary></entry></feed>